Previously on "Transformers Prime"...
在上一集里
The specimen you see before you was bred in the laboratory,
你眼前的样本是在实验室中培养的
Cloned from fossilized remains, Which I discovered on Cybertron.
是由我在塞博特恩挖掘出的化石克隆而来
A dragon? Where'd the 'cons get a dragon?
龙？虎子什么时候弄到了一条龙？
Ultra Magnus? It's an honor.
通天晓？很荣幸见到您
"it's an honor, sir."
要说 很荣幸见到您“长官”！
We must stop Megatron. With or without Optimus Prime.
我们必须阻止威震天 无论擎天柱在与不在
Who put shoulderpads in command?
是谁让这个垫肩男当家的？
Ultra Magnus is the only logical choice.
通天晓是唯一合乎逻辑的人选
Optimus! I have the forge!
擎天柱 我拿到卓天越之锤了
Whatever power remains... must be used to restore Cybertron.
它残余的能量必须用于复苏塞博特恩
The time for a new leader is upon us.
新领袖诞生的时刻已经到来！
I believe that leader... stands before me right now.
我坚信他此刻就站在我面前！
Autobots.
汽车人们
We remain vastly outnumbered, and, despite our munitions,
目前我们在人数上仍然处于劣势 抛开弹药情况不谈
Do not currently possess the firepower necessary to compromise the Decepticon citadel.
我们也缺乏足够的火力去摧毁霸天虎的堡垒
Uncle sam's military does.
山姆大叔的军队倒是有足够的火力
I just can't let them make a move as long as Megatron's ray guns are pointed at washington.
但我无权调动 否则威震天的巨炮会把华盛顿夷为平地
Then we must infiltrate darkmount, in order to nullify its fusion cannons.
那么首先我们必须潜入黑山堡垒 摧毁那些融合加农炮
Unfortunately, it seems the fortress is heavily shielded against unauthorized groundbridges.
不幸的是 那座堡垒屏蔽了所有未经授权的环陆桥出口
Even those originating from Decepticon technology.
即使霸天虎自己的环陆桥技术也不例外
Guess we'll have to sneak past enemy lines.
看来我们得从敌人眼皮底下硬闯了
Wrecker-style.
以雷霆救援队的方式
I couldn't deal with "wrecker-style" back on Cybertron,
早在塞博特恩时 我就难以接受你们的行为
and I refuse to deal with it here.
所以现在我仍不会批准
Hmm.
哼
Now, we require a means of thinning the Decepticon ranks to even the odds,
我们需要尽可能地将霸天虎调离老巢 以增加胜算
If we're to have any hope of completing this mission...
只有这样才有希望完成这次任务
or of surviving it.
或者说 幸存下来
I-I can't do this.
我…我做不到
I mean, sure, who wouldn't wanna be a prime?
我是说 没错 谁不想当领袖呢？
But I'm really not ready for that kind of responsibility.
但我真的还没有做好准备 去承担那种责任
Smokescreen...
烟幕…
The choice is neither yours, nor mine to make.
你无权作出选择 我也一样…
When it is time...
当时机到来时…
The matrix of leadership will present itself only to one whose spark is worthy.
领导模块会在它所认可的火种面前现身
Because it worked so well last time...
这个方法上次效果不错
I knew the humans couldn't resist using their telecommunications.
我就知道人类控制不住使用移动通讯设备的欲望
That is all they seem to do.
他们似乎干什么都离不开它
Seek and destroy!
找到他 加以消灭
I have five bogeys converging right on top of jack.
有五个虎子正向杰克的位置集结
Not anymore.
不再是了
Miko, your turn.
神子 该你出场了
Hello, I need two large pies,
你好 我要两个大号披萨
Sicilian.
西西里口味
You deliver, right?
你们能送餐吧？
Hm hm ha ha ha... Humans.
哼哼 人类啊
Standby to groundbridge.
准备环陆桥
Soundwave,
声波
why can't you accept a little good fortune?
当你人品爆发时 咋就无法接受它呢？
The Autobots couldn't possibly stay hidden forever.
汽车人不可能永远跟我们躲猫猫
I really could have used that pizza.
我真的很想吃那个披萨
I've tapped into the Decepticon communications network.
我已经接入霸天虎的通讯网络了
Are you ready, Jack?
杰克 你准备好了吗？
Decepticon command, do you read me?
咳咳 霸天虎指挥中心 收到请回答？
I remain unconvinced.
我觉得还不够逼真
I will enhance your performance with static.
我会用静电伪装 使其以假乱真
Decepticon command, do you read? We are under autobot attack!
霸天虎指挥中心 请回答 我们正遭受汽车人的进攻！
It's one of our energon mines!
那里是我们的能量矿！
Insecticons, prepare for battle!
机器昆虫 做好战斗准备！
Autobots, lock and load!
汽车人们 子弹上膛！
Keep your engines warm, boys.
把引擎都给我开着 小伙子们
We launch the moment Ultra Magnus gives the all-clear.
一旦我们接到通天晓的信号 就立即出发！
There must be some mistake, commander Starscream.
红蜘蛛指挥官 信息有误
The mine is not under attack.
矿工们并未遭受攻击
What? How can that--? Starscream!
- 什么？怎么可能？ - 红蜘蛛！
Explain why my forces are scattering across this globe.
解释一下为什么我的军队目前散落在全球各地？
Uh, renegade Autobot mischief, lord Megatron!
是那些该死的汽车人搞的鬼 威震天陛下
I am in the process of deducing how they are infiltrating our communications systems without the base of--
我仍在分析他们是如何侵入我们的通讯系统 却没有触发…
The Harbinger!
先驱号！
You left abandoned Decepticon technology fully operational and unsecured?
你竟把一艘能正常运行的霸天虎飞船 丢在那里不管不顾？
Allow me to correct my oversight immediately.
呃…请允许我 立即去弥补自己的疏忽
Seeker armada to the flight deck.
追踪者部队到飞行甲板集合
Your target is the Decepticon ship, the Harbinger.
你们的目标是霸天虎飞船――先驱号
You are to obliterate it, at once!
立即去把它轰成渣！
My armada is in position.
我的大军已经就位
Open a groundbridge to the Harbinger.
打开通向先驱号的环陆桥
Since it would seem that darkmount is under attack,
看来黑山堡垒目前正遭受攻击
kindly redirect all efforts toward ensuring that our invaders our eradicated!
调集所有留守力量 消灭入侵者
Fire in another hole!
再吃我一颗！
I assure you, master,
我向您保证 我的主人
I have everything under control.
一切都在我的掌控之中
Lord Megatron.
威震天陛下
I accept that military considerations are outside of my domain,
我承认军事行动并非我的专长
But perhaps it is once again time... to release the Predacon.
但似乎再次释放巨狰狞的时机已到
Ratchet, now!
救护车 动手！
Oh, well...
这下可好
Yes, that's right. Go off and sulk, why don't you?
对 去吧 找个没人的地方生闷气吧
Who stands before me?
是谁站在我的面前？
What? It's me, Optimus.
什么？是我啊 擎天柱
Smokescreen.
我是烟幕
Who... beckons...?
谁…在召唤我…
Come, Optimus.
来吧 擎天柱
Is it truly you...
真的是您吗？
Alpha Trion?
钛师傅
I stand before you, my student.
既然我出现在你面前 我的高徒
As such, it would seem that it is your time.
说明你的大限将至
Why do you hesitate?
你为何有所犹豫？
I do not fear joining with the allspark,
我并非畏惧回归火种源
but for the fate of the matrix of leadership.
但是…我担忧领导模块的归属
You know as well as I, a worthy candidate is near.
你我都了然于心 一位优秀的人选就在眼前
One who will learn to be a prime, as you once did.
他会成长为一名合格的领袖 就像当初的你一样
Ultra Magnus to stealth team.
通天晓呼叫突击小队
Status report.
汇报目前状况
Having a little trouble reaching the objective.
任务轻微受阻
Security is tighter than anticipated, sir.
守卫比预想的要多 长官！
Keep them occupied.
继续拖住他们！
Ultra Magnus.
通天晓
Allow me to venture: You intend to disarm my fusion cannons by disabling their power core.
让我猜猜 你想毁掉融合炮的能量核心 使其瘫痪
Indeed, Megatron,
没错 威震天
and you are standing in my way.
而你正挡在我的路上
Your mission was most illogical.
你们的行动毫无逻辑可言
Scrap.
糟糕！
Ultra Magnus.
通天晓…
You are no Optimus Prime.
你毕竟不是擎天柱
What in the name of Paul Revere's Horse is taking them so long?
看在保罗・里维尔坐骑的份儿上 怎么这么久还没消息？
All invaders have been taken captive, master.
所有入侵者都已被捕 主人
There was no sign of Optimus Prime.
但并没有发现擎天柱的踪迹
So tell me, commander...
那么 告诉我 指挥官
Where might your leader be?
你们的首领到底在哪儿？
Take my hand, Optimus, and join me.
握紧我的手 擎天柱 与我重聚
Join with the allspark.
回归火种源吧
Optimus, no!
擎天柱 不！
This isn't how the story's supposed to end.
故事不该以这种结局收场
I will not ask again!
我不会再问第二遍
If I knew, I wouldn't tell you.
即使我知道 也不会告诉你
Very well.
很好
Execute our prisoners, and fire each cannon at the nearest metropolis within its sites.
处死所有的俘虏 启动融合炮攻击射程内最近的大型城市
It is time to show the known universe that this planet belongs to Megatron.
我要让整个宇宙知道 这颗星球是属于我威震天的
Master, something's coming!
主人 有不明物体接近
Predacon?
巨狰狞？
Hm... not beasty enough.
嗯…长得没那么邪乎
How is that possible?
这怎么可能？
What?
什么？
An Autobot signal. But it's airborne.
一个汽车人信号 但却是个飞行单位？
I know that color scheme.
我认识那个涂装
Wait! He can't fly! Can he?
等等！他不会飞啊 难道不是吗？
Commander?
指挥官？
Sir, you're looking... robust.
长官 您看起来…强壮无比
It is paramount that we disable the fusion cannons below.
我们的当务之急是瘫痪下面的融合加农炮
Understood.
明白了
All units... Optimus Prime has returned.
全员注意 擎天柱回归了
- Yes! - Awesome! - Thank the allspark! - Sweet!
- 太棒了！ - 好极了！ - 感谢火种源！
I repeat, Prime is alive and quite well.
我重复一遍 擎天柱还活着 并且状态极佳
Yes!
好哎！
Optimus!
擎――天――柱！！！
Commander, a cluster of enemy signals, incoming!
指挥官 大量敌对信号迫近！
Ah! Humans.
哼 人类！
Activate the fusion cannons!
启动融合加农炮！
Sky Strikers, await my command.
空中霸王战机 等待我的指令
Megatron,
威――震――天！
begone!
给我消失吧！
Autobots, clear the area.
汽车人们 撤离该地区
Let's do this.
动手吧！
Soundwave, I require a groundbridge.
声波 请求开启环陆桥
Transport lord Megatron to the warship.
把威震天陛下转移到战舰上去
What are you doing?
你在干什么！
No! We will not retreat!
不！我们绝不撤退！
This battle is lost, my liege.
我们已经输掉了这场战斗 我的君王
We must retreat if we are to have any hope of winning the war.
如果我们还想有翻盘的机会 现在必须撤退！
Aw, I missed it!
啊！我错过正戏了！
On behalf of the president and the joint chiefs,
我谨代表美国总统和美军联合参谋本部
I thank you all for your selfless heroism in defense of this planet.
感谢你们在守卫这颗星球时所表现出的大无畏精神
I'm sorry the world can't know of your undying dedication,
非常遗憾 你们的杰出贡献仍无法被公诸于世
because I, for one, owe you my life, my liberty, and my future.
但对我个人来说 我欠你们一条命 一份自由 还有一个未来
Sir, I am honored to relinquish command of the Autobots to you.
长官 我非常荣幸地将汽车人的指挥权交还给您
Welcome to earth, Ultra Magnus.
欢迎来到地球 通天晓
And to team prime.
也欢迎你加入领袖卫队
Okay, someone's gotta say it.
好吧 这句话我憋了好久了
Optimus 2.0 is rad!
擎天柱2.0版酷毙了！
Imagine what the forge could do for your bod.
想想卓天越之锤可以把你们改成什么样
Is it true that the forge has been drained of its power?
卓天越之锤的能量真的完全耗尽了吗？
Then any hope of rebuilding the Omega Lock has truly been lost.
那么重铸终极之锁已经彻底无望了
I did what I felt was right.
我…我做了自己认为对的事
And your instincts have again proven to be quite sound.
那么你再次证明了你的直觉是正确的
Yeah!
耶！